Kishan Narotam



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (Electrical) Information

University of the Witwatersrand Johannesburg, South Africa 2019

IEB National Senior Certificate with Advanced Programme Mathematics

St John's College Johannesburg, South Africa 2012

INDUSTRIES

Logistics & Market Research

Education & Training

ICT (Information & Communication Technologies)

Engineering

Insurance



Gender · Male

Disability · None

Race · Indian

Languages · English

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Information (**Electrical**) **Engineer** currently employed as an *Associate Consultant* at *IQbusiness*, with a drive in the corporate environment and the desire to apply himself to his maximum potential. Having worked on various projects where his role ranged from lead engineer to a business analyst and to a data analyst, Kishan's approach to work is methodical and analytical. The execution of the task is planned accordingly, to complete all objectives in the most efficient and successful manner so that the maximum value can be added.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant · IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa

- Completed the internal school and training programme, known as BasIQs.
- Researched, and collaborated on an internal project for a talent management solution as a business analyst.
- Contracted out to research, analyse and test data for Genex Insights.

Teaching Assistant · University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2019 - 10/2019 07/2018 - 10/2018

Responsibilities: Kishan was required to help run, execute and demonstrate laboratories and tutorials. In doing so he required extensive knowledge of C++, SFML, GitHub and Git collaboration. Throughout the course, Kishan assisted the students in a variety of ways relating to their work.

Intern · Liberty Life Head Office | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2017

28/11/2016 - 18/01/2017

06/05/2016 - 17/06/2016

Responsibilities: Kishan worked in the IT department of the company assisting the HOD in various projects. The projects tasked to Kishan ranged from data collection, database management, network mapping, system analysis, C++ and VBA programming and Excel programming.

Intern · MICROS South Africa (Pty) Ltd | Johannesburg, South Africa # 26/06/2015 - 03/07/2015

Responsibilities: Kishan was challenged with analysing C# code for an ongoing project and was tasked with converting the project into C++. Following this, Kishan had to design and implement a basic user interface for the analysed code.

Kishan Narotam

</> TOOLKIT

Software Development

MATLAB; C++; Java; HTML; CSS; NodeJS; Assembly; Python

Project Management

Scrum; Kanban; MS Project; Trello; Test Driven Development

Databases

MySQL; MS Access

Continuous Integration

Git

Analysis

MS Excel

Technical Writing

MS Word; MS PowerPoint; MS Outlook; MS Visio; LaTeX

CERTIFICATES

RPA Business Analyst Training · UiPath Academy 12 May 2020

ICAgile Certified Professional · ICAgile 04 May 2020

Complete Introduction to Business Data Analysis Udemy 09 March 2020

RPA Starter Training · UIPath Academy 03 March 2020

International Computer Driving Licence (ICDL) · ECDL Foundation 04 May 2012

ONLINE PROFILE

in /in/kishan-narotam-b829aa49/

/KNarotam

== PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst · MultiChoice Africa Genex Insights | Johannesburg, South Africa ## 09/03/2020 - Current

Project Overview: One of Genex Insights' largest clients is MultiChoice Africa, and the project involved investigating discrepancies between data, along with developing various methodologies that will allow the team to become more proactive in handling the account.

Responsibilities: Kishan was placed as a Data Analyst within the Genex Insights' CX team. Kishan's main responsibility was investigating data discrepancies and utilising the Genex Insights VOC platform. Kishan is currently assisting the team in developing a way forward that will allow the team to become more efficient and deliver more value to their clients.

Business Analyst · IQbusiness Talent Management Solution IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa

06/02/2020 - 25/02/2020

Project Overview: IQbusiness required a proposal for a solution which would aid in the improvement of their current talent management processes, allowing employees and managers to monitor personal development and talent.

Responsibilities: Kishan was part of the business requirements team, whose responsibility was focused on creating the business requirements document, by consolidating prior teams work. Kishan was also part of the governance team and took control of consolidating the project initiation document for the final proposal, as well as presenting the final proposal.

Business Analyst · IAM AfricaAccess | CSO Testing Proposal Absa | Johannesburg, South Africa

30/01/2020 - 04/02/2020

Project Overview: The IAM project was an enhancement on Absa's existing Access Management System, which looked into adding an amend capability. The testing project looked at proposing an idea for a separate testing team to be created within Absa's CSO team.

Responsibilities: Kishan worked as a Junior business analyst, and his responsibilities involved creating the initial draft of the business requirements document. The testing project involved creating a proposal for the testing team based on research and best practices.

Lead Engineer · Design of a Thermally Controlled System for Medications University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

17/09/2019 - 25/10/2019

Project Overview: The project involved designing a thermal system that can control the temperature of medication in it. The design was unique based on current literature and simulated in a multiphysics programme.

Co-Lead Engineer · Image Compression Based on Non-Parametric Sampling in Noisy Environments

University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

01/07/2019 - 11/09/2019

Project Overview: The aim of the project was to create a method of image compression that involved creating holes in the image, encoding, transmitting said image through a noisy channel and filling these holes.